<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jobs on Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/</link><description>Recent content in Jobs on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:33:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:33:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:29:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Samurai Savage Best In Slot: 2.14 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,201 DPS] Etro
2.14 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,029 DPS] Etro
28 GCD loop, two filler GCDs, most used sets. Play these.
2.07 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,102 DPS] Etro
2.07 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [22,933 DPS] Etro
29 GCD loop, three filler GCDs, beginner friendly due to Gekko/Kasha filler, can only iai-weave on ping ≤ 10ms without clipping.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:28:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Table of Contents [Table of Contents]
[Introduction]
[The 5.0 Samurai Rotation Changes]
Tsubame Gaeshi is Restrictive and Inflexible [The Crumbs: Normalised Cooldown Times] [The Solution: A Rotation Loop] [Optimising Potency]
[Maximising Yukikaze Combo Usage] [Maintaining GCD Count]</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:27:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</guid><description>Is X better than Y for me?
For weapons: item level (ilvl)/weapon damage (wd) wins, regardless of substats. For armor: ilvl usually wins, unless 5 materia slots. For same-ilvl pieces: substat itemization can be in your favor or not depending on the rest of your gear and stat tiering. When in doubt, use the Gear Planner - only here can you get an accurate answer for your setup!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:26:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</guid><description>Samurai Standard Openers: Higanbana First: Standard
Single Weave
Video Example
Your standard opener which, due to the earlier DoT application, is ahead in output for the majority of any given encounter.
Midare First: Standard
Single Weave
Video Example
Should be reserved for encounters with a phase or kill time such that you are able to land an additional Midare/Tsubame where Higanbana first would not.
Samurai Non-Standard Openers: Alternative Higanbana First: Standard</description></item><item><title>SAM Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:24:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Weaponskills (GCD) Hakaze Single target combo starter. 200 potency. +5 Kenki. Jinpu Single target second step combo. 100 potency, 320 potency if combo from Hakaze. Combo Bonus: Increases damage dealt by 13% for 40s, +5 Kenki. Shifu Single target second step combo. 100 potency, 320 potency if combo from Hakaze.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:18:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</guid><description>Updated by Sweaty Boxer of Midgardsormr
FFXIV: Shadowbringers Patch 5.25, April 2020 With thanks to members of the Balance Discord for discussion and theorycrafting (Jahudant and Boxer) Images and icons are properties of Square Enix Foreword With the release of Shadowbringers, Samurai is now celebrating two years in the game, and with Aureum’s permission I’m taking over as caretaker for this guide. The 5.0 update brings with it several changes to both Samurai and melee as a whole, but due to the nature of this guide, I will be introducing them for players new to the job.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:18:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Level 50 Level 50 Opener
Keep buffs up, reapply your Higanbana as close to zero as possible, Midare goes brrrrrr.
Level 52 You learn Kenki Mastery I, which introduces the Kenki gauge and positionals on Gekko/Kasha. Use Kaiten exclusively on Iaijutsu (Higanbana &amp;gt; Midare).
Level 60 Level 60 Opener
Use the above and read Level 52 for the rest.
Level 62 You learn Kenki Mastery II. Begin to Kaiten all Iaijutsu, use excess Kenki on Shinten, use Level 70 Openers.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:50:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions Why can’t I fit five GCDs in Blood Weapon (or Delirium)? The single most likely reason is that you aren’t weaving Blood Weapon late into the GCD. As long as you are weaving Blood Weapon late and keeping the GCD rolling during it, five GCDs in Blood Weapon should be very consistent. With high latency (100+ ms), double weaves can cause the last GCD to fall out of Blood Weapon.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:44:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Dark Knight Best In Slot Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS sets will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on what gear is available to you. Prioritizing item level over substats is generally recommended while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:43:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/advanced-guide/</guid><description>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition An advanced guide to the class Last Update: 11/09/2019 - E3S, E4S added. Additional information on Salted Earth added.
Hi! Emiin Vanih [Lamia] here. Myself and my companions have developed a compendium of information that will hopefully help you take your Dark Knight playstyle to a new level. While tanking is easy to learn, with the right know-how, you can excel at the role, and lead your group to victory.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:35:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers/</guid><description>Dark Knight Openers and Rotation Openers DRK has a several different options for openers, not all of which are listed here. Fight timings and party composition can both affect which opener is best, based on when you can keep uptime on the boss and when raid buffs are used. Fight-specific opener information can be found in #drk_encounter and #drk_questions (often in the pins). This section will list some General-purpose DRK openers which work relatively well in most situations.</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:34:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</guid><description>Dark Knight Skills and Abilities Overview Tank Stance Grit
Toggle - Ten second cooldown after toggling on • No cooldown for toggling off Multiplies enmity (aggro, hate, etc) generation by ten Keep this on in dungeons or as the current maintank (in content with more than one tank) Single Target GCDs Souleater Combo
200 &amp;gt; 300 &amp;gt; 400 potency
Hard Slash Syphon Strike: +600 MP Souleater: +20 Blood, 300p heal Bloodspiller</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction to Dark Knight The useless pre-Endwalker guide by nikroulah#1605 Introduction
Skills and Abilities Overview
Tank Stance
Single Target GCDs
Abilities (oGCDs)
Buffs Offensive Defensive or Utility AoE
Other Actions (Infrequently Used)
Opener
Rotation
Using Blood Weapon and Delirium Pooling Resources for Raid Buffs Helpful Macros</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction First off, a word of warning: Do not use the gear given out by the first job quest. It is normal-quality, meaning it is significantly weaker than other gear of the same item level. The Steel Cuirass (ilvl30), for example, has about the same defense as a high-quality Iron Scale Mail (ilvl 23).
While this guide is not intended as a complete resource for tanking in dungeons, the following section will provide a brief primer for those new to the role.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:04:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5 AST BiS SETS https://bit.ly/astgearcalc
So we&amp;rsquo;re here, finally with a proper writeup.
Making BiS was expected to be very difficult this tier with AST&amp;rsquo;s new affinity for SpS&amp;hellip;but instead it actually was quite easy. Avoid Piety like the plague and there you go, there&amp;rsquo;s your BiS pieces.
Higher Piety sets also have the nice consolation of having a wealth of Crit (rather than the traditional disgusting amounts of Det) so it won&amp;rsquo;t even feel that bad to swap to lower damage for the sake of Piety.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-guide/</guid><description>So, you&amp;rsquo;re (hopefully) comfortable with the fundamentals of Astrologian. Now, it’s time to talk details: quirky mechanics, important interactions, and optimization. We’ll start with the most straightforward topics and work up to the more complicated ones.
Sect Swapping/Stance Dancing In dungeons, you can swap to Nocturnal Sect after the last enemy in a pull dies, apply a shield to the tank in preparation for the next pull, and then swap back to Diurnal Sect.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:58:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/faq/</guid><description>What Sect Should I Use? Diurnal remains generally very efficient, but buffs to Celestial Opposition and Celestial Intersection reduce the reliance on GCD healing (which is where Nocturnal Sect primarily falls short of Diurnal), and Nocturnal Intersection is very strong. The gap in overall efficiency between Diurnal and Nocturnal Sect is still quite significant, but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t put you off of using Nocturnal Sect when the situation calls for it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:51:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers/</guid><description>Opener The most up to date Astrologian opener(s) can always be found in the #ast_resources channel on The Balance Discord. Keep in mind that Astrologian openers are extremely flexible and depend almost entirely on the circumstances of the fight, the timings of the planned raid DPS bursts, and party composition. Any premade Astrologian opener is a generic framework, not a universally optimal opener.
We&amp;rsquo;ve taken a lot of care to evaluate as many of the variables as we reasonably can and identify the core methodology of the most statistically successful opener with regard to when most DPS jobs burst the hardest and when other raid buffs should be coming out, assuming everyone is doing a proper opener.</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:48:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/skills-overview/</guid><description>PvE actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Malefic 1 Spell 400 1.5s 2.5s Deals unaspected damage with a potency of 150. Benefic 2 Spell 400 1.5s 2.5s Restores target&amp;rsquo;s HP. Combust 4 Spell 400 Instant 2.5s Deals unaspected damage over time. Lightspeed 6 Ability Instant 90s Reduces cast times for spells by 2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/basic-guide/</guid><description>Intro to Astrologian Who Needs MP When You’re This Pretty? Brought to you by Zyrkhan Dar’locke, AKA Literally Who
No, we still can’t be Gambit
The Scope of this Guide As the title implies, this guide is intended to function as an introduction to Astrologian. This guide is concerned with Astrologian only. It will not address the general principles of healing as they apply to all healers. Those things are discussed in Zyrk’s Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 02:02:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description>BiS: &amp;ldquo;Speed 3655 SpS Tier (Relic)&amp;quot;:
https://etro.gg/gearset/1c64d9a9-892b-48a8-b7d1-f760839d659c
&amp;ldquo;Crit 2030 SPS Tier (Relic)&amp;quot;:
https://etro.gg/gearset/b470c4c6-6f4a-47c8-8162-52ac09494e02
&amp;ldquo;SMN/RDM-Friendly BiS&amp;rdquo;: (can use the SMN/RDM BiS without swapping melds)
Use the &amp;ldquo;Speed 3655 SpS&amp;rdquo; Tier set for BLM, and use SMN/RDM BiS on the other casters. Shared pieces between the sets have no meld conflicts.
Thanks to incoherent#0649 for the provided relic sets!
Please see http://bit.ly/BLMGear for additional sets, including non-relic BiS sets
&amp;ldquo;TEA BiS&amp;rdquo;: (Please look at the sheet below under &amp;ldquo;Patch 5.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:57:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: September 19, 2021
Introduction
Basics
Intermediate
Advanced
Appendix
Introduction Hello. I am Reina, a caster player, and I am standing on the shoulders of giants. This document aims to provide a comprehensive guide on non-standard rotation (also known as AI or Hypermeme rotation). There is the assumption you know all of the basics of BLM, including abbreviations and fundamentals. If not, refer to the BLM Basic Guide before proceeding here.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:53:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/faq/</guid><description>Q: What is Umbral Soul used for? A: Purely a downtime tool, a better version of Transpose. Lets you build back up to Umbral Ice III + Three Umbral Hearts during downtime, so you can Thunder III -&amp;gt; Fire III when you can hit something again. If you end a fight in Astral Fire, Transpose into UI so you can use Umbral Soul. Do not use Umbral Soul during uptime.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:51:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers/</guid><description>Openers Openers should put abilities on cooldown, fit strong spells within buff windows, and minimize clipping. All openers assume there is a pull countdown and the boss is pulled at zero. If your group pulls earlier, adjust them as necessary. Use the highest tier Tincture / Infusion / Potion of Intelligence available.
With all openers being very close in estimated output over the course of the entire encounter, it is instead recommended to choose your opener based on your current spellspeed, with consideration towards potential fight-specific requirements.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:49:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>PvE actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Blizzard 1 Spell 400 2.5s 2.5s Deals ice damage with a potency of 180. Fire 2 Spell 800 2.5s 2.5s Deals fire damage with a potency of 180. Transpose 4 Ability - Instant 5s Swaps Astral Fire with a single Umbral Ice or Umbral Ice with a single Astral Fire.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:47:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: October 26, 2019
General Info Openers Single Target Rotation Recovery and Reopeners AoE Rotation (3+ Targets) Movement and Uptime Spell Speed Thresholds Leveling Rotations Macros About Gear Appendix Misc. My IGN is Caro Kann, and I’m a BLM main (now SCH (AND NOW AST) :pepega:) and this is my guide for playing 5.X BLM. In this guide, I go over the basics of the BLM rotation and offer some potential optimizations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 01:45:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Single Target Leveling Rotation Before Level 40 Fire spam until low MP &amp;gt; Transpose &amp;gt; Thunder &amp;gt; Blizzard until max MP &amp;gt; Transpose
Level 40-59 Blizzard III &amp;gt; Thunder III &amp;gt; (Optional T3 for MP tick) &amp;gt; Fire III &amp;gt; F1 spam until low MP &amp;gt; Repeat
Note: Use F3 and T3 procs as you get them, but don&amp;rsquo;t cancel casts to use procs.
Level 60-71 B3 &amp;gt; Blizzard IV &amp;gt; T3 &amp;gt; F3 &amp;gt; F4 (x3) &amp;gt; F1 &amp;gt; F4 (x3) &amp;gt; Despair &amp;gt; Repeat</description></item><item><title>Advanced Astrologian Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-astrologian-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-astrologian-guide/</guid><description>So, you&amp;rsquo;re (hopefully) comfortable with the fundamentals of Astrologian. Now, it’s time to talk details: quirky mechanics, important interactions, and optimization. We’ll start with the most straightforward topics and work up to the more complicated ones.
Sect Swapping/Stance Dancing In dungeons, you can swap to Nocturnal Sect after the last enemy in a pull dies, apply a shield to the tank in preparation for the next pull, and then swap back to Diurnal Sect.</description></item><item><title>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/an-in-depth-look-at-dark-knight-shadowbringers-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/an-in-depth-look-at-dark-knight-shadowbringers-edition/</guid><description>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition An advanced guide to the class Last Update: 11/09/2019 - E3S, E4S added. Additional information on Salted Earth added.
Hi! Emiin Vanih [Lamia] here. Myself and my companions have developed a compendium of information that will hopefully help you take your Dark Knight playstyle to a new level. While tanking is easy to learn, with the right know-how, you can excel at the role, and lead your group to victory.</description></item><item><title>AST Openers and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Opener The most up to date Astrologian opener(s) can always be found in the #ast_resources channel on The Balance Discord. Keep in mind that Astrologian openers are extremely flexible and depend almost entirely on the circumstances of the fight, the timings of the planned raid DPS bursts, and party composition. Any premade Astrologian opener is a generic framework, not a universally optimal opener.
We&amp;rsquo;ve taken a lot of care to evaluate as many of the variables as we reasonably can and identify the core methodology of the most statistically successful opener with regard to when most DPS jobs burst the hardest and when other raid buffs should be coming out, assuming everyone is doing a proper opener.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</guid><description>Intro to Astrologian Who Needs MP When You’re This Pretty? Brought to you by Zyrkhan Dar’locke, AKA Literally Who
No, we still can’t be Gambit
The Scope of this Guide As the title implies, this guide is intended to function as an introduction to Astrologian. This guide is concerned with Astrologian only. It will not address the general principles of healing as they apply to all healers. Those things are discussed in Zyrk’s Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/black-mage-leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/black-mage-leveling-guide/</guid><description>Single Target Leveling Rotation Before Level 40 Fire spam until low MP &amp;gt; Transpose &amp;gt; Thunder &amp;gt; Blizzard until max MP &amp;gt; Transpose
Level 40-59 Blizzard III &amp;gt; Thunder III &amp;gt; (Optional T3 for MP tick) &amp;gt; Fire III &amp;gt; F1 spam until low MP &amp;gt; Repeat
Note: Use F3 and T3 procs as you get them, but don&amp;rsquo;t cancel casts to use procs.
Level 60-71 B3 &amp;gt; Blizzard IV &amp;gt; T3 &amp;gt; F3 &amp;gt; F4 (x3) &amp;gt; F1 &amp;gt; F4 (x3) &amp;gt; Despair &amp;gt; Repeat</description></item><item><title>BLM Advanced Non-Standard Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-non-standard-blm-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-non-standard-blm-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: September 19, 2021
Introduction
Basics
Intermediate
Advanced
Appendix
Introduction Hello. I am Reina, a caster player, and I am standing on the shoulders of giants. This document aims to provide a comprehensive guide on non-standard rotation (also known as AI or Hypermeme rotation). There is the assumption you know all of the basics of BLM, including abbreviations and fundamentals. If not, refer to the BLM Basic Guide before proceeding here.</description></item><item><title>BLM Basic Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: October 26, 2019
General Info Openers Single Target Rotation Recovery and Reopeners AoE Rotation (3+ Targets) Movement and Uptime Spell Speed Thresholds Leveling Rotations Macros About Gear Appendix Misc. My IGN is Caro Kann, and I’m a BLM main (now SCH (AND NOW AST) :pepega:) and this is my guide for playing 5.X BLM. In this guide, I go over the basics of the BLM rotation and offer some potential optimizations.</description></item><item><title>BLM Raid Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-4-blm-raid-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-4-blm-raid-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: February 2, 2021
General Info Eden’s Promise: Umbra (Savage) Eden’s Promise: Litany (Savage) Eden’s Promise: Anamorphosis (Savage) Eden’s Promise: Eternity (Savage) Phase 1 Eden’s Promise: Eternity (Savage) Phase 2 General Info Some initial suggestions for Ley Lines usage and other fight-specific information/recommendations. They are not guaranteed to universally be the best way to do the fights, and based on various factors like kill time, optimization, positioning/strats, etc.</description></item><item><title>Bushido: A PvE Samurai Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/bushido-a-pve-samurai-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/bushido-a-pve-samurai-guide/</guid><description>Updated by Sweaty Boxer of Midgardsormr FFXIV: Shadowbringers Patch 5.25, April 2020 With thanks to members of the Balance Discord for discussion and theorycrafting (Jahudant and Boxer) Images and icons are properties of Square Enix Foreword With the release of Shadowbringers, Samurai is now celebrating two years in the game, and with Aureum’s permission I’m taking over as caretaker for this guide. The 5.0 update brings with it several changes to both Samurai and melee as a whole, but due to the nature of this guide, I will be introducing them for players new to the job.</description></item><item><title>Expert: The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Table of Contents [Table of Contents]
[Introduction]
[The 5.0 Samurai Rotation Changes]
Tsubame Gaeshi is Restrictive and Inflexible [The Crumbs: Normalised Cooldown Times] [The Solution: A Rotation Loop] [Optimising Potency]
[Maximising Yukikaze Combo Usage] [Maintaining GCD Count]</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Dark Knight</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/introduction-to-dark-knight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/introduction-to-dark-knight/</guid><description>Introduction to Dark Knight The useless pre-Endwalker guide by nikroulah#1605 Introduction
Skills and Abilities Overview
Tank Stance
Single Target GCDs
Abilities (oGCDs)
Buffs Offensive Defensive or Utility AoE
Other Actions (Infrequently Used)
Opener
Rotation
Using Blood Weapon and Delirium Pooling Resources for Raid Buffs Helpful Macros</description></item><item><title>Leveling</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling/</guid><description>Introduction First off, a word of warning: Do not use the gear given out by the first job quest. It is normal-quality, meaning it is significantly weaker than other gear of the same item level. The Steel Cuirass (ilvl30), for example, has about the same defense as a high-quality Iron Scale Mail (ilvl 23).
While this guide is not intended as a complete resource for tanking in dungeons, the following section will provide a brief primer for those new to the role.</description></item><item><title>Openers</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Openers Openers should put abilities on cooldown, fit strong spells within buff windows, and minimize clipping. All openers assume there is a pull countdown and the boss is pulled at zero. If your group pulls earlier, adjust them as necessary. Use the highest tier Tincture / Infusion / Potion of Intelligence available.
With all openers being very close in estimated output over the course of the entire encounter, it is instead recommended to choose your opener based on your current spellspeed, with consideration towards potential fight-specific requirements.</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Samurai Standard Openers: Higanbana First: Standard
Single Weave
Video Example
Your standard opener which, due to the earlier DoT application, is ahead in output for the majority of any given encounter.
Midare First: Standard
Single Weave
Video Example
Should be reserved for encounters with a phase or kill time such that you are able to land an additional Midare/Tsubame where Higanbana first would not.
Samurai Non-Standard Openers: Alternative Higanbana First: Standard</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Dark Knight Openers and Rotation Openers DRK has a several different options for openers, not all of which are listed here. Fight timings and party composition can both affect which opener is best, based on when you can keep uptime on the boss and when raid buffs are used. Fight-specific opener information can be found in #drk_encounter and #drk_questions (often in the pins). This section will list some General-purpose DRK openers which work relatively well in most situations.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Leveling Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/samurai-leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/samurai-leveling-guide/</guid><description>Level 50 Level 50 Opener
Keep buffs up, reapply your Higanbana as close to zero as possible, Midare goes brrrrrr.
Level 52 You learn Kenki Mastery I, which introduces the Kenki gauge and positionals on Gekko/Kasha. Use Kaiten exclusively on Iaijutsu (Higanbana &amp;gt; Midare).
Level 60 Level 60 Opener
Use the above and read Level 52 for the rest.
Level 62 You learn Kenki Mastery II. Begin to Kaiten all Iaijutsu, use excess Kenki on Shinten, use Level 70 Openers.</description></item><item><title>Savage</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/savage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/savage/</guid><description>E9S - Cloud of Darkness
E10S - Shadowkeeper
E11S - Fatebreaker
E12S - Eden&amp;rsquo;s Promise
E12S - Oracle of Darkness
E9S Optimizations Sample Clear Recommended Opener Use Higanbana First or Midare First opener.
Bramble Strat There&amp;rsquo;s no opener that fits the no-uptime strat for Brambles, so use an uptime strat, or you will get disconnected mid-burst.
Cross Brambles
Square Brambles
Handling Anti-Air and Wide-Angle The following clips show examples of how to manage both of these mechanics with minimal-to-no interruption.</description></item><item><title>Savage Encounter Tips</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/savage-encounter-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/savage-encounter-tips/</guid><description>General Tips Eden&amp;rsquo;s Promise features a number of mechanics that apply damage down on failure, with failure determined as the mechanic causing damage to your HP bar. Because of this condition, it is possible to negate the damage downs by absorbing the entire hit with a shield, such as TBN.
The mechanics where this is most commonly useful are:
E9S: Anti-Air Phaser Unlimited (&amp;ldquo;AA Chariot&amp;rdquo;)
E10S: Throne of Shadow (&amp;ldquo;Doggo Standup&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;Sword Chariot&amp;rdquo;)</description></item><item><title>Skill Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skill-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skill-overview/</guid><description>PvE actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Blizzard 1 Spell 400 2.5s 2.5s Deals ice damage with a potency of 180. Fire 2 Spell 800 2.5s 2.5s Deals fire damage with a potency of 180. Transpose 4 Ability - Instant 5s Swaps Astral Fire with a single Umbral Ice or Umbral Ice with a single Astral Fire.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>About Gear Optimizing substats gives the least return on DPS when compared to being proficient at your job, having high uptime, handling mechanics efficiently, etc.
BLM has no bad substats.
Infinite resources and lack of damaging oGCDs makes Spell Speed a strong stat. More SpS can make the job feel smoother to play and make Fire Phases less strict. Aim for higher iLvl gear and get SpS to personal preference and comfort level.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Astrologian Stats and Materia What should I meld? Outside of Best in Slot, your meld priority should be;
Piety to comfort (if needed) Sps if you want to hit a certain GCD tier Crit Det/dh Sps. That said, the difference between meld setups is so small overall that you could opt for Det over Crit, or take more Spell Speed than usual if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re more comfortable with during prog.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Samurai Substat Priority Pre-Level 80:
iLvl &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; Direct Hit &amp;gt; SKS &amp;gt; Crit = DET
Level 80 Pre-BIS:
iLvl &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; SKS* &amp;raquo; Crit ≥ Direct Hit &amp;gt; DET
*To one of the recommended SkS ranges. See the Advanced Guide for full explanation.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Stat Priority Item Level
Affects Strength and Weapon Damage (for weapons) Significantly affects all damage dealt Prioritize over substat type Critical Hit
Priority meld on all gear (unless already capped on that piece) Skill Speed
Meld only to reach preferred GCD speed (enough to consistently get 5 GCDs in Blood Weapon) #bot_spam !xivmath rspeed 2.43 or see the tiers below Direct Hit Rate</description></item><item><title>Ultimates</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/ultimates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/ultimates/</guid><description>The Unending Coil of Bahamut General: Ultimates are riddled with downtime mechanics and thus there is no loop to follow. The general idea for Ultimates is to map out your rotation for each phase and be as optimal as possible in the usage of your Meikyo Shisui and Higanbana (and Tsubame for level 80). In stark comparison to Savage that also means you generally want to avoid the usage of Hagakure unless it&amp;rsquo;s required for you to start a phase with a specific Sen setup.</description></item><item><title>Ultimates</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/ultimates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/ultimates/</guid><description>The Unending Coil of Bahamut (UCoB) Gearing For level 70 Ultimates, a full set of synced gear with Critical Hit + Determination and enough pieces with Critical Hit + Skill Speed to hit your desired GCD tier is more than sufficient. All pieces of item level 418 or higher will max out both substats in UCoB. Gear from the Swallow&amp;rsquo;s Compass dungeon and +2 Eureka armor matches the item level sync and may provide a small boost.</description></item></channel></rss>