<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/</link><description>Recent content on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 03:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Paladin Best in Slot Gear Priority and Pre-BiS Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on personal loot availability. Prioritizing item level over substats is encouraged while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title>Paladin FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 17:10:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/faq/</guid><description>Why is Circle of Scorn used immediately in the opener?
Circle of Scorn is used before Fight or Flight in most openers and kept on cooldown in most phases for two reasons:
Its short cooldown (25 seconds) is equal to the duration of Fight or Flight, meaning one CoS usage should always occur during FoF regardless of their respective timings, given full uptime. Its high DoT uptime (~60%) means that any delays are likely to cost ticks at the end of the phase, resulting in a potency loss overall.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:35:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Advanced Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:32:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/advanced-guide/</guid><description>This section assumes that you are comfortable with the entirety of the Paladin kit, as well as the basic rotation outlined in the Intro &amp;amp; Rotation Guide.
If that is not the case, please turn back.
Introduction to Paladin Optimization Because Paladin&amp;rsquo;s self-buffs (Fight or Flight and Requiescat) are very powerful compared to raid buffs (e.g. Trick Attack, Divination), much of Paladin optimization focuses around maximizing usages of personal buff windows within a given phase or killtime, sometimes at the cost of raid buff contribution.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:29:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/openers/</guid><description>Paladin Opener and Rotation Tanks currently use Grade 4 Tinctures of Strength (Strength also affects tank magic potency, including healing)
Quick Opener/Rotation Graphic: Alternative In-Depth Graphic: 60 Second Rotation Paladin&amp;rsquo;s natural rotation is approximately 63 seconds long, which means Fight or Flight and Requiescat (both with 60-second cooldowns) are delayed by 1 GCD per minute. In some situations this can cost FoF GCDs or even a Confiteor usage before the end of a phase, and in long encounters with minimal downtime, physical oGCDs must eventually be delayed as well to stay lined up with FoF.</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/skills-overview/</guid><description>Buffs Iron Will
Toggle • 10s cooldown after toggling on • no cooldown for toggling off
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.)
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank)
Fight or Flight
60s cooldown
+25% physical damage for 25 seconds
By using Fight or Flight late into the GCD (just before the next GCD), it is possible to fit 11 physical GCDs into the buff window.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:23:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/basic-guide/</guid><description>the useless pre-Endwalker guide update by nikroulah#1605
Skills and Abilities Overview Buffs Iron WillToggle | 10s cooldown after toggling on. | No cooldown for toggling off.
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.).
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank).
Fight or Flight60s cooldown.
+25% physical damage for 25 seconds.
By using Fight or Flight late into the GCD (just before the next GCD), it is possible to fit 11 physical GCDs into the buff window.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 08:20:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Paladin Levelling in Dungeons Keeping Aggro Turn on Iron Will and never turn it off. As long as you keep hitting the mobs, you will have aggro on them. In multi-target situations, use AoE so that you can keep aggro on all mobs.
Pulling Mobs There are a variety of ways to ensure you pull all of the mobs in a pack quickly and reliably, without stopping on your way to the next pack of mobs.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Paladin Shadowbringers Edition</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/introduction-to-paladin-in-shadowbringers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/introduction-to-paladin-in-shadowbringers/</guid><description>the useless pre-Endwalker guide update by nikroulah#1605
Skills and Abilities Overview Buffs Iron Will
Toggle • 10s cooldown after toggling on • no cooldown for toggling off
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.)
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank)
Fight or Flight
60s cooldown
+25% physical damage for 25 seconds</description></item><item><title>Leveling and Dungeons</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/levelling-and-dungeons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/levelling-and-dungeons/</guid><description>Keeping Aggro Turn on Iron Will and never turn it off. As long as you keep hitting the mobs, you will have aggro on them. In multi-target situations, use AoE so that you can keep aggro on all mobs.
Pulling Mobs There are a variety of ways to ensure you pull all of the mobs in a pack quickly and reliably, without stopping on your way to the next pack of mobs.</description></item><item><title>Opener and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/opener-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/opener-and-rotation/</guid><description>Paladin Opener and Rotation Tanks currently use Grade 4 Tinctures of Strength (Strength also affects tank magic potency, including healing)
Quick Opener/Rotation Graphic: Alternative In-Depth Graphic: 60 Second Rotation Paladin&amp;rsquo;s natural rotation is approximately 63 seconds long, which means Fight or Flight and Requiescat (both with 60-second cooldowns) are delayed by 1 GCD per minute. In some situations this can cost FoF GCDs or even a Confiteor usage before the end of a phase, and in long encounters with minimal downtime, physical oGCDs must eventually be delayed as well to stay lined up with FoF.</description></item><item><title>PLD 5.5 Extreme Fight Tips</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/extreme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/extreme/</guid><description>The Cloud Deck (Extreme) Fight GCD spreadsheet
This encounter is particularly killtime-dependent to set up an optimal final phase re-opener during the last few miniphases. Shown here is the fastest practical re-opener, for a kill around x:50-x:00. For later kills on the minute (9:00, 10:00, etc), simply use a standard rotation after 415 seconds.
For kills at different spots in the minute (8:30, 9:30, etc), adjustments can be made after four minutes to delay Fight or Flight and Requiescat for a different re-opener without losing a usage.</description></item><item><title>PLD Savages</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/savages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/savages/</guid><description>Current Savage Tier Optimization Umbra (E9S) Optimal rotation is kill-time dependent. With standard opener, both phasers in the first phase should align with Requiescat. Use Hallowed Ground for uptime on the post-tiles phaser.
Litany (E10S) Optimal rotation is kill-time dependent. To align the disengage for the second Throne of Shadow with Requiescat, we prefer 3-second prepull FoF opener with 60-second loop until Void Gate.
For downtime cup game dogs, hardcast Holy Spirit at the wall and drop an Atonement, provided you are not mid-combo.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Paladin Stats and Materia Note: This priority is also applicable to customizable (&amp;ldquo;relic&amp;rdquo;) Augmented Law&amp;rsquo;s Order weapons (515) and Blade&amp;rsquo;s weapons (535) for current content, before best-in-slot is obtained, excluding direct hit rate (which cannot be added to these weapons). Use the Tank Gear Manager to make educated gearing and melding decisions with precise stat tiering in mind.
Physical Damage (weapon only)
Significantly affects all damage dealt Always proportional to item level Cannot be melded Strength</description></item><item><title>Ultimates</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/ultimates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/ultimates/</guid><description>The Epic of Alexander (TEA) Phase optimization Phase 1 - Living Liquid &amp;amp; Liquid Hand Phase GCD spreadsheet
Delayed opener is optimal for this phase, but fast pushes may require a standard opener to ensure buffs and MP are available for Phase 2. Paladin should pull Liquid Hand, but does not necessarily need to hold the Hand all phase.
Phase 2 - Brute Justice &amp;amp; Cruise Chaser Party-specific. Pre-pull FoF (6th Hawk Blaster) is optimal for this phase.</description></item></channel></rss>